The Resume of

MD TAMZID HASAN

North South University Bashundhara R/A Dhaka- 1229, Bangladesh thunique1988@gmail.com +880 1711 927924 Portfolio: www.tamzid.info



Objective

To build up a career in the technical field, concentrating on research and development in order to boost production. My integrity and devotion to work motivated me to learn and share knowledge within the team, where multitasking, strong leadership, and interpersonal communication skills are most important.

Experience

Jhpiego Bangladesh

Project on Maternal Immunization Readiness Initiative.

Consultant

January 2023 to February 2024

Jhpiego Bangladesh

Develop a Health Facility Readiness Assessment Tool (HFRA)

for Maternal Immunization (MI).

Contributor

March 2023 to January 2024

Department of Public Health, North South University Myopia and dry-eye disease among the female students of NSU.

NSU Global Health Institute
People's perception, experience, and usage of health facilities.

Qualitative Data Collector
November 2023

NSU Global Health Institute USAID's Community-Health-Systems Strengthening Activity (CHSS).

Department of Public Health, North South University PTSD, Insomnia, and Suicidal Ideation among the firefighters of Bangladesh.

NSU Global Health Institute
North South University

Department of Public Health, School of Health & Life Science North South University

Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology Performance Analysis of Boost Inverter for using in PV system.

S. S. Engineering & Construction Builders, developers, & construction.

GS Engineering & Construction Bibiyana to Kaliakoir 400KV overhead transmission line supervised by PGCB. October 2023

Research Assistant

Project Work September 2023

Thesis Work

November 2023

Research Assistant August 2022 to December 2023

Graduate Teaching Assistant June 2022 to January 2023

> Thesis Work June 2018

Electrical Engineer October 2013 to July 2017

Supervision of Project April 2013 to August 2013











Portfolio: www.tamzid.info

GS Engineering & Construction Engineering & Construction

Electrical Engineer April 2013 to August 2013

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd

Designing & Installation of 10 kWp solar system with 3 hrs battery backup at MCC, Mymensingh.

Project Monitoring May 2012

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd

Installation of 2.55 kWp solar system with 4 hrs battery backup at ARC Architect, Dhaka, Bangladesh.

Project Monitoring March 2012

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd

Installation of 1.2 kWp solar system with 2 hrs battery backup at Jafrabad, Dhaka, Bangladesh.

Project Monitoring February 2012

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd Renewable energy system

Assistant Engineer November 2011 to July 2012

Education

MPH in Epidemiology

BSc in EEE

North South University

2021 – 2022

Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology

2006 – 2011

Honors & Scholarships

University scholarship for MPH program
Scholarship awarded to attend the study session of Peace in the
Spotlight in Strasbourg, France.
Scholarship awarded to attend the project management training in
the frame of Peers to Peace in Athens, Greece.

North South University

Council of Europe

Erasmus+ Scholarship

Skills

Skills are developed by professional and academic work. And good collaboration with EPI, MNC&AH, DGHS, MoHFW, Bangladesh, and other international organisations.

Research Skills

- Conduct study, proposal writing, study design, sample estimation.
- Monitoring & Evaluation the project or program.
- Grand proposal writing for the fund and development of the project.
- Transcription and translation of IDIs, KIIs, and FGDs.

Development Skills

- ♦ Develop a Health Facility Readiness Assessment Tool for Maternal Immunization in Bangladesh.
- Assist faculty members in the preparation of different module development.
- Prepare reports and design specifications, conduct research, and supervised the team.

Coordinating Skills

- ♦ Assist faculty members with classroom instruction, exams, record keeping, and other miscellaneous projects and develop course plans.
- Assist academic staff with the development or update of learning materials, proctor exams, and record grades in the grade book.
- Survey the site and manage the design and construction of electrical systems.

Training Skills

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info











- Tutor or mentor students in class or outside.
- Prepare reports and design specifications, conduct research, and training.
- Supervised and trained project team members.

Computer Skills

- Data analysis and visualization with R, Rstudio, and STATA.
- End Note, Zotero, and Mendely for reference management.
- MS Office (Word, Excel, and Powerpoint) & LaTEX writing tools.

Scientific Work

Journal Publication

Md. Shafiqul Islam, Syed Muhammad Baqui Billah, Jewell Ilias Rab, Abir Dey, Md. Habib Naziat, and Md. Tamzid Hasan (2024): Prevalence of Diabetic Retinopathy and Associated Risk Factors in the Southern Region of Bangladesh. International Journal of Human and Health Sciences. DOI: http://dx.doi.org/10.31344/ijhhs.v8i2.640

Azaz Bin Sharif, **Md Tamzid Hasan**, Syed Sharaf Ahmed Chowdhury, and Satyajit Kundu (2023): *Inequalities in early initiation of breastfeeding in Bangladesh: An estimation of relative and absolute measures of inequality.* International Breastfeeding Journal. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13006-023-00584-y

Azaz Bin Sharif, **Md Tamzid Hasan**, Md. Habib Naziat, Tahmina Zerin, and Satyajit Kundu (2023): *Permanent, long-acting, and short-acting reversible contraceptive methods use among women in Bangladesh: An analysis of Bangladesh Demographic and Health Survey 2017-2018 data.* BMJ Open 2023;13:e073469. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2023-073469

Md Jakaria Rahimi, **Md Tamzid Hasan**, Ripan Kumar Dhar, Md Shaheer Ibne Islam, Khatune Jannat Siddiqua, and Shahriar Azgar (2011): *Performance Analysis of Boost Inverter for Photovoltaic System*. IJETSE International Journal of Emerging Technologies in Science and Engineering, Vol.5, No.2, Dec 2011.

Skills Development Work

Training & Workshops

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info

"Life course nutrition: Maternal and child health strategies in public health" by Northwest Center for Public Health Practice.

Certificate of "Environmental Health in Disasters" by South Central Public Health Partnership from School of Public Health and Tropical Medicine

Online training course on "Good Clinical Practice Training for Social and Behavioral Research." *SBM Tracking ID: 50453*

Water, sanitation and hygiene for the prevention and care of neglected tropical diseases

The Food Insecurity and Health Readiness and Response Strategic Framework by WHO department of Nutrition and Food Safety

Hypothesis-driven approach- Problem solving in the context of global health by Health Emergencies Programme on WHO

Inequality monitoring in sexual, reproductive, maternal, newborn, child and adolescent health by WHO division of Data, Analytics and Delivery for Impact

School of Public Health, University of Washington

Tulane University and The University of Albama at Birmingham

Society of Behavioral Medicine (SBM)

World Health Organization (WHO)

World Health Organization (WHO)

World Health Organization (WHO)

World Health Organization (WHO)











Health inequality monitoring foundations: Overview, Data sources, Health data disaggregation, Summary measures of health inequality, and Reporting by WHO division of Data, Analytics and Delivery for Impact

(WHO)

World Health Organization

A training on 'Mastering Monitoring, Evaluation, Accountability, Learning-Transferring Knowledge into Practice.'

MEAL Perspective Hub

"Monitoring Coverage Data at the Health Facility Level" and "Change Management"

Immunization Academy

DHS capacity building workshop on 'Using the DHS Dataset into Research' proposed by USAID.

Department of Public Health, NSU

A training on 'Scientific Writing' organized by School of Health & Life Science, North South University.

Global Health Institute, NSU

Workshop on 'How to develop an analytical plan for a research project- the gateway of writing a manuscript' organized by The Global Health Network Asia.

icddr'b

A training on 'Peace in the Spotlight' organized by SCI & VYRE.

Council of Europe

A training on 'Project management in the frame of the Peers to Peace' co-funded by the Europe for Citizens Program of the EU.

SCI

Volunteering Work

Major Activities

CERIA Farm International Work Camp in Ipoh, Perak at Malaysia.

International Work Camp IN-SCI 11.10 on Achalam Eco ashram- From Ego to Eco (EE01) in Tiruvannamalai, Tamil Nadu at India.

International Work Camp NP-SCI 13.4 on Help in Reconstruction of School Building in Balthali, Panauti at Nepal.

International Work Camp BD-SCI 11.5 on Climate & Sustainable Lifestyle with River Erosion Affected Community in Shibchar, Madaripur.

SCI Malaysia SCI India & SCI Hong Kong SCI Nepal

Membership

Member of Public Health Association of Bangladesh (PHAB).	2022
Member of Public Health and Science Club, North South University.	2021
Vice President of ANIMESH a social organization.	2021
Member of The Institution of Engineers, Bangladesh (IEB). Memership No. M/34701.	2012
Volunteer Coordinator of Service Civil International- Bangladesh (SCI-BD).	2015
Member of Service Civil International- Bangladesh (SCI-BD).	2007

Referees

Available upon request.

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info









